export const ANIMALHUSBANDRYA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The botanical name for Guinea grass is",
A: "Andropogon gayanus",
B: "Cynodon dactylon",
C: "Panicum maximum",
D: "Pennisetum purpureum",
answer: "A. Andropogon gayanus",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The incubation period for the egg of turkey is",
A: "15 days",
B: "21 days",
C: "28 days",
D: "32 days",
answer: "C. 28 days",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The live stock marketing chain begins with the",
A: "consumer",
B: "producer",
C: "retailer",
D: "wholesaler",
answer: "B. producer",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Anaemia in piglets could be prevented by providing them with",
A: "red soil",
B: "antibiotics",
C: "common salt",
D: "vitamins",
answer: "A. red soil",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Browsing by ruminants is the act of",
A: "chewing the cud",
B: "feeding in groups",
C: "unsupervised grazing",
D: "picking leaves from shrubs",
answer: "D. picking leaves from shrubs",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Candling is done in a hatchery in order to remove",
A: "dirty eggs",
B: "small eggs",
C: "broken eggs",
D: "infertile eggs",
answer: "D. infertile eggs",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following livestock disease affect the reproductive system?",
A: "Anthrax",
B: "Brucellosis",
C: "Mastitis",
D: "Rinderpest",
answer: "B. Brucellosis",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. In order to prevent bulls from eating during traction, they should be",
A: "branded",
B: "dehorned",
C: "muzzled",
D: "tethered",
answer: "C. muzzled",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following pairs of factors must be effectively controlled in artificial incubation?",
A: "Temperature and humidity",
B: "Ventilation and turning",
C: "Temperature and light",
D: "Light and ventilation",
answer: "A. Temperature and humidity",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The part labelled I is called",
A: "antenna",
B: "eye",
C: "foot",
D: "tentacle",
answer: "B. eye",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following uses are associated with the part labelled II?  \nI. Decoration  \nII. Feed ingredient  \nIII. Liming",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "C. II and III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The edible parts are labelled",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "C. II and III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Which of the following products could be obtained from the farm animal iIIustrated?",
A: "Bone",
B: "Choven",
C: "Fur",
D: "Shell",
answer: "C. Fur",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Which of the following statements about artificial insemination is not correct?",
A: "The offspring are always healthier than the parents.",
B: "It enables the use of semen after the death of the donor",
C: "It reduces the spread of sexually transmitted diseases",
D: "incapacitated males could be used",
answer: "A. The offspring are always healthier than the parents.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Which of the following feed ingredients is used to improve the quality of egg shell?",
A: "Di- calcium phosphate",
B: "Fish meal",
C: "Copra cake",
D: "Mineral premix",
answer: "A. Di- calcium phosphate",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Unlike local breeds of goats, exotic breeds are usually",
A: "small in size",
B: "fast growing",
C: "black in colour",
D: "more resistant to diseases",
answer: "B. fast growing",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following factors is no considered when selecting livestock?",
A: "Egg production",
B: "Feed consumption",
C: "Body weight",
D: "Mortality",
answer: "D. Mortality",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Which of the following statements is an advantage of the battery cage system of poultry production?",
A: "Rate of egg production is high",
B: "Thick shelled eggs are produced",
C: "Egg picking is prevented",
D: "Eggs which cannot be hatched are produced",
answer: "A. Rate of egg production is high",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The correct way of lifting a large rabbit is by grasping the skin over the",
A: "lion",
B: "neck",
C: "shoulder",
D: "thigh",
answer: "C. shoulder",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Some farm animals do not require vitamin B in their diet because it",
A: "is synthesized by microbes in their rumen",
B: "interferes with the metabolism of fat",
C: "is not essential for their growth",
D: "is not normally absorbed",
answer: "A. is synthesized by microbes in their rumen",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. In poultry production, incubators are used to supply heat to",
A: "day-old chicks for faster growth",
B: "fertilized eggs of chick development",
C: "cocks to increase their libido",
D: "sick birds in cold weather",
answer: "B. fertilized eggs of chick development",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following domestic fowls require the highest amount of protein in their diet?",
A: "Chicks",
B: "Cocks",
C: "Growers",
D: "Hens",
answer: "A. Chicks",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. New-born livestock should be fed with colostrums mainly because it",
A: "is easy to digest by animals",
B: "contains nutrients for survival",
C: "contains antibodies for protection",
D: "Is the first milk produced",
answer: "C. contains antibodies for protection",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following factors adversely affect feed utilization and productivity in poultry?  \nI. High fibre content of feed  \nII. Low calcium diet  \nIII. Water deprivation",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "D. I, II and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The equipment used in concentrating heat for chicks during brooding is",
A: "chick guard",
B: "hover",
C: "lamp",
D: "thermometer",
answer: "B. hover",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following factors does not influence the distribution of farm animals in west Africa?",
A: "climate",
B: "Culture",
C: "Disease",
D: "Topography",
answer: "D. Topography",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The correct order in which food moves through the digestive system of the domestic fowl is",
A: "crop → gizzard → proventriculus → duodenum",
B: "Crop → Proventriculus → gizzard → duodenum",
C: "Proventriculus → crop → gizzard → duodenum",
D: "proventriculus → gizzard → crop →duodenum",
answer: "B. Crop → Proventriculus → gizzard → duodenum",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which of the following diseases usually occur during brooding of chicks?  \nI. Yolk sac infection  \nII. Coccidiosis  \nIII. Fowl pox",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "l, II and III",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. One of the reasons for dehorning cattle is to",
A: "help to identify animals in the herd",
B: "improve the growth rate of the bulls",
C: "ease handling of animals",
D: "prevent disease in the herd",
answer: "C. ease handling of animals",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The diagram above is an illustration of the life cycle of a farm animal. At which stage will lactation start?",
A: "I",
B: "II",
C: "Ill",
D: "IV",
answer: "C. III",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Feed waste by birds in deep litter house could be minimized by",
A: "providing guards for feeding troughs",
B: "reducing the number of feeding troughs",
C: "using plastic feeding troughs",
D: "using different sizes of feeding troughs",
answer: "A. providing guards for feeding troughs",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Rinderpest in cattle could be prevented by",
A: "applying fungicide",
B: "vaccinating regularly",
C: "dipping in acaricide",
D: "provision of balance diet",
answer: "B. vaccinating regularly",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following factors should be considered in the siting of a pig sty?  \nI. Slope of the land  \nII. Vegetation cover of the land  \nIII. Direction of the sun",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "D. I, II and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The ration which provides just enough energy for normal physiological processes to take place in farm animals is known as",
A: "balance ration",
B: "production ration",
C: "maintenance ration",
D: "daily ration",
answer: "C. maintenance ration",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Pasture of goats should contain some shrubs to provide opportunity for them to",
A: "graze",
B: "browse",
C: "obtain protein",
D: "excursive themselves",
answer: "B. browse",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following animals have large litter size?  \nI. Grasscutter  \nII. Pig  \nIII. Rabbit",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "C. II and III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The objective of flushing in female livestock is to",
A: "increase chance of multiple birth",
B: "improve disease resistance",
C: "promote muscle development",
D: "enable animals to come on heat",
answer: "A. increase chance of multiple birth",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Wing-web injection is administered to four weeks old chicks in order to prevent",
A: "fowl pox",
B: "fowl typhoid",
C: "coccidiosis",
D: "Newcastle disease",
answer: "A. fowl pox",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The needle teeth of piglets are removed in order to",
A: "make piglets grow faster",
B: "prevent injury to the teat of sows",
C: "allow piglets to suckle sufficient milk",
D: "prevent piglets from biting the farmer",
answer: "B. prevent injury to the teat of sows",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. All the offspring of the first generation of farm animals would be tall if the gene for tallness is",
A: "dominant",
B: "mutated",
C: "recessive",
D: "superior",
answer: "A. dominant",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. The quality of natural pasture could best be improved by",
A: "burning the grass",
B: "practicing zero grazing",
C: "practicing mulching",
D: "introducing legumes",
answer: "D. introducing legumes",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Temperature breeds of livestock which are imported to the tropics could suffer from",
A: "worm infestation",
B: "excessive rain",
C: "heat stress",
D: "frost bite",
answer: "C. heat stress",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Which of the following statements about pasture intended for use as silage is correct?",
A: "It is prone to pest attack after flowering",
B: "The nutrient content decreases after flowering",
C: "Lush legumes and grass should be used",
D: "Fibre content is high before flowering",
answer: "C. Lush legumes and grass should be used",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Deficiency of vitamin K in farm animals causes",
A: "delayed blood clotting",
B: "sterility in females",
C: "night blindness",
D: "rickets",
answer: "A. delayed blood clotting",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Fumigation of incubator and disinfection of brooder house are aimed at preventing",
A: "fowl cholera",
B: "fowl pox",
C: "gumbro",
D: "salmonellosis",
answer: "D. salmonellosis",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. If the weight of a goat increased from 19kg to 39kg in 3 months, determine the average monthly weight gain",
A: "6.7kg",
B: "3.0 kg",
C: "19.3 kg",
D: "20.0 kg",
answer: "A. 6.7kg",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The device which helps to regulate temperature in an incubator is the",
A: "hygrometer",
B: "insulator",
C: "thermometer",
D: "thermostat",
answer: "D. thermostat",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Which of the following stomach compartments secretes digestive enzymes in ruminants?",
A: "Abomasum",
B: "Omasum",
C: "Reticulum",
D: "Rumen",
answer: "A. Abomasum",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. In which part of the digestive system of poultry is cellulose digested?",
A: "caecum",
B: "Crop",
C: "Intestine",
D: "Proventriculus",
answer: "A. caecum",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The development of the embryo in farm animals takes place in the",
A: "infandibulum",
B: "oviduct",
C: "ovary",
D: "uterus",
answer: "D. uterus",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]